(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-12T22:21:55.712560",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
倍の倍のFIGHT！
Double, double FIGHT!
倍 倍 倍 倍 キャンディチュウ！
Double, double, double, double Candy Chu!
倍の倍のFIGHT！
Double, double FIGHT!
倍 倍 倍 倍 キャンディチュウ！
Double, double, double, double Candy Chu!
倍の倍のFIGHT！
Double, double FIGHT!
倍 倍 倍 倍 キャンディチュウ！
Double, double, double, double Candy Chu!
倍の倍のFIGHT！
Double, double FIGHT!
本音と建前 ない私
I have no distinction between my true feelings and public face.
なりたい ありたい けど だけど
I want to be, I want to exist as I am, but...
人の目気にせず 素直な子
An honest girl who doesn't care what others think.
なりたい ありたい けど だけど
I want to be, I want to exist as I am, but...
誰かを救うということは 過去の自分も救うことです
Saving someone means saving your past self too.
誰かを愛すということは 本当の自分を大好きになることです
Loving someone means truly coming to love yourself.
倍！ 倍！ 倍！ 倍！ 倍！ 倍！ 倍！ 倍！ FIGHT！
Double! Double! Double! Double! Double! Double! Double! Double! FIGHT!
何回転んでも 立ち上がれ
No matter how many times you fall, stand back up!
倍！ 倍！ 倍！ 倍！ 倍！ 倍！ 倍！ 倍！ FIGHT！
Double! Double! Double! Double! Double! Double! Double! Double! FIGHT!
厄介な問題も 飛び越えろ
Leap over troublesome problems too!
嬉しい 楽しい
Happy! Fun!
ほら倍の倍の倍の倍で
Look, double by double by double by double,
もっといこうよ FIGHT！ FIGHT！ FIGHT！ FIGHT！ FIGHT！ FIGHT！ FIGHT！ FIGHT！
let's keep going! FIGHT! FIGHT! FIGHT! FIGHT! FIGHT! FIGHT! FIGHT! FIGHT!
飽き性 根性ない上京
Easily bored, lacking willpower coming to the big city,
やめたい やめたい けど だけど
I want to quit, I want to quit, but...
もっぱらネガティブ 自虐思考
Mostly negative, self-deprecating thoughts,
やめたい やめたい けど だけど
I want to quit, I want to quit, but...
何かを犠牲にする事は 何かを目指すと言う事です
Sacrificing something means aiming for something else.
何かを目指すと言う事は 何かを本気で信じると言う事です
Aiming for something means truly believing in something.
倍！ 倍！ 倍！ 倍！ 倍！ 倍！ 倍！ 倍！ FIGHT！
Double! Double! Double! Double! Double! Double! Double! Double! FIGHT!
なんてステキな この人生
What a wonderful life this is!
倍！ 倍！ 倍！ 倍！ 倍！ 倍！ 倍！ 倍！ FIGHT！
Double! Double! Double! Double! Double! Double! Double! Double! FIGHT!
だって私は そう 私だもん
Because I am... well, me!
楽しい 愛しい
Fun! Precious!
ほら倍の倍の倍の倍で
Look, double by double by double by double,
もっといこうよ FIGHT！ FIGHT！ FIGHT！ FIGHT！ FIGHT！ FIGHT！ FIGHT！ FIGHT！
let's keep going! FIGHT! FIGHT! FIGHT! FIGHT! FIGHT! FIGHT! FIGHT! FIGHT!
倍の倍のFIGHT！
Double, double FIGHT!
倍 倍 倍 倍 キャンディチュウ！
Double, double, double, double Candy Chu!
倍の倍のFIGHT！
Double, double FIGHT!
倍 倍 倍 倍 キャンディチュウ！
Double, double, double, double Candy Chu!
倍の倍のFIGHT！
Double, double FIGHT!
倍 倍 倍 倍 キャンディチュウ！
Double, double, double, double Candy Chu!
倍の倍のFIGHT！
Double, double FIGHT!
倍 倍 倍 倍 キャンディチュウ！
Double, double, double, double Candy Chu!
自分を大事に 本能を大事に つまずいたって
Value yourself, value your instincts, even if you stumble—
強い人間になりたかったって 今からなれるさ
Even if you wanted to be strong, you can become strong starting now!
有言実行 言葉に宿った 魂信じて
Action follows words—believe in the soul residing in your words!
誰かと比べて落ち込んだって 自分は自分さ
Even if you feel down comparing yourself to others, you are you!
半径100km 幸せで満たしたいな
Within a 100km radius, I want to fill it with happiness!
生きてるだけでスゴい事だから 命を褒めよう
Just being alive is amazing, so let's praise life!
出来ない事より出来る事 ほら数えてみようよ
Instead of what you can't do, count what you can do!
すなわちとにかく倍々アクティブ
In other words, just keep being doubly active!
倍倍FIGHT!
Double-Double FIGHT!
バイバイバイ ほんの小さな一歩
Bye-bye-bye, a tiny little step,
バイバイバイ 大きな大きな一歩
Bye-bye-bye, a big, big step,
バイバイバイ どれも君にとって
Bye-bye-bye, each and every one to you...
大切な
is a precious,
大切な勇気の証だよ
precious proof of courage!
何と言われてもあきらめぬ
No matter what anyone says, don't give up!
人生これきり一度きり
You only get one life!
何回転んでも立ち上がれ
No matter how many times you fall, get back up!
厄介な問題も飛び越えろ
Jump right over troublesome problems!
嬉しい
Happy!
楽しい
Fun!
ほら倍の倍の倍の倍でも乗り越えよう
Come on, let's overcome it, doubled and doubled again!
いっせーのーせー！
One, two, go!
険しい道も共に歩むんだ You will never walk alone
We'll walk down tough paths together; you will never walk alone!
つまずいてもがいて強くなるんだ
Stumble, struggle, and grow stronger!
険しい道も共に歩むんだ You will never walk alone
We'll walk down tough paths together; you will never walk alone!
つまずいてもがいて強くなるんだ
Stumble, struggle, and grow stronger!
明日からじゃなくて今日だ 今だ 君だ ここだ！
Not tomorrow, but today, right now, you, right here!
弱気になって疲れたならちょっと休むかい？
If you're feeling down and tired, why not rest a bit?
私たちがいつもそばにいるからさ
Because we'll always be by your side!
はい、君たち～！
Hey, everyone~!
7周年記念ライブ始まりましたねー！
The 7th Anniversary Live Stream has started!
ハッシュタグは、えー、こちら、こちら、こちら
The hashtag is, um, this, this, this...
#宝鐘マリン7周年3DLIVE になっております！
It's #宝鐘マリン7周年3DLIVE!
この後ね
After this,
知ってると思うけど、水着のお披露目が
as you probably know, we have the swimsuit reveal,
ありますので！3D水着、楽しみでしょう？
so look forward to the 3D swimsuit!
いっぱいスクショしてツイートしてくだ...あ、ポスト！
Take lots of screenshots and Tweet... ah, Post!
ポストしてください！
Please post them!
ここから先も
From here on as well,
まだまだ素敵なゲストの皆さん
we still have wonderful guests coming,
来ますので！一体どんな曲、
so stay tuned to see what songs
どんなパフォーマンスをするのか、超超楽しみに！
and performances they'll do!
そして水着もどんな感じなのか、
And check out what the swimsuits look like,
差分もいっぱいあるからね！あの、差分も全部見切ってから
because there are lots of variations! Make sure you watch every single one!
そして素敵な...
And we also have wonderful...
うん、グッズもね、マリンがいっぱい考えた
yeah, merch that Marine put a lot of thought into,
グッズとかもありますんで！
so please check out the merch too!
さあ、どんどん楽しんでいきましょう！いくぞー！
Now then, let's keep having fun! Let's go~!
Lonely ロリロリ神、降臨
Lonely, the loli-loli god descends!
鐘を鳴らせばこの通り
Ring the bell and behold,
これは救済のレクイエム
This is a requiem of salvation!
せーのっ
Ready, set, go!
触ったら逮捕！
Touch me and you're arrested!
極chu♡で点呼
Extreme chu♡ roll call!
いち にー さん しー？
One, two, three, four?
ごーめーんーなーさーい
"I'm sorry~"
ごめんなさいが、聞こえなーい
I can't hear your apology!
粛聖！ロリ神レクイエム
Purification! Loli God Requiem
将来は お前なんか に好かれたくない
In the future, I don't want to be liked by someone like you!
泥水で 口を洗え 法廷で 会おう？
Wash your mouth out with muddy water, see you in court!
さぁ おまわりさん 連れて行って
Come on, police officer, take them away,
妄想しか取り柄のない かわいそうな人
Such a pathetic person whose only merit is delusion!
その姿親に見せられますかー？
Can you show that appearance to your parents?
わぁ、ありがとう、お疲れ様ですー^^
Wah, thank you, good work~^^
ロリロリ神、降臨
Loli-loli god descends!
マジヤバ奴等に用心
Beware of seriously dangerous folks!
まともじゃないなら 早く消えてください
If you're not normal, hurry up and disappear!
Lonely ロリロリ神、降臨
Lonely, the loli-loli god descends!
鐘を鳴らせばこの通り
Ring the bell and behold!
歳も優しくて 素敵なお兄ちゃん
An older brother who is kind and wonderful for his age,
楽園でホラ ねんねしな
Now go to sleep right here in paradise!
ほら。世の中には、こんなに気持ち悪い人たちが蔓延っているんですっ！
Look. In this world, such creepy people are running rampant!
みーんな、晒しageますよ。
We're gonna expose them all online!
触ったら逮捕！
Touch me and you're arrested!
極chu♡で点呼
Extreme chu♡ roll call!
いち にー さん しー？
One, two, three, four?
ごーめーんーなーさーい
"I'm sorry~"
ごめんなさいが、聞こえなーい
I can't hear your apology!
粛聖！ロリ神レクイエム
Purification! Loli God Requiem
はぁーい、獄中にいるみなしゃぁーん
Hiii everyone in prison~~!
刑務所ファンミーティングのお時間でぇーす
It's time for the prison fan meeting!
その、腐りきった耳をゴリゴリかっぽじって
Clean out those rotten ears of yours
よぉーく聞いてくださいね
And listen very carefully!
助かる〜
Ah, so helpful~
うるさい
Shut up.
黙ってもらっていいですか？
Could you please keep quiet?
キモいです
You're gross.
かわいそう
How pathetic.
助かる〜
So helpful~
どーした？ 弱っ！ みっともな！
What's wrong? So weak! Pathetic!
出し様もない お兄ちゃん お姉ちゃん
Hopeless big brothers and big sisters...
マジ半端ないゴミだな お前ら
You guys are seriously total trash.
アブっ！ 消毒100KB！
Oops! Disinfection 100KB!
これ警戒態勢発動！
Alert system activated!
粛清
Purge!
ういビーム！
Ui Beam!
もっちょ
Once more!
ういビーム！
Ui Beam!
まだまだ！
Not yet!
怒りの日 せめて怒りの日 死ぬ雨が降る日 愚かな心は 骨の髄まで浄化する一筋の... これが ういビームなのです！
Day of wrath, the day of judgment, where dead rain falls; a single ray to purify foolish hearts to the core... This is the Ui Beam!
ういは全てを許します
Ui forgives everything.
あぁ あぁ
Ah, ah...
この世の醜さを 集めて描いてみるよ
I'll gather the ugliness of this world and paint it out.
真っ白なキャンバス
On a pure white canvas...
汚れてない態度
With an untainted attitude.
論理 振り向いた少女は そっと手を掴む
The girl who turned back logic softly takes your hand...
救いなどないから
Since there is no salvation...
大きなお友達のみんなへ！
To all my big friends out there!
お前らが打ち込んでいる虚無には何の意味があるの？
What meaning is there in the void you're sinking into?
ねえ、教えてよ！
Hey, tell me!
マリン、ぜんぜん分かんないんだ！
Marine doesn't understand at all!
ろり ろり 神降臨
Loli, loli, God descent!
さよなら 笑顔でバイバイ
Goodbye, bye-bye with a smile!
ピリオドのあと
Even after the period...
届かなくて教えてあげる
Since it doesn't reach you, I'll teach you.
ろり ろり ろり 神降臨
Loli, loli, loli, God descent!
鐘を鳴らして どこ辿り
Ringing the bell, where do we end up?
とても優しくて 素敵なお兄ちゃん
You're such a kind and wonderful big brother.
楽園でほら ねんねしな
Here, go to sleep in paradise.
それが救済の
That is salvation's...
レクイエム
Requiem.
せーの！ さまさまさまほー！ 毒中で成功！ 1, 2, 3, 4!
Ready, set! Sama-sama-samaho! Poison success! 1, 2, 3, 4!
ごめんなさい ごめんなさいが聞こえない！
Sorry, sorry, I can't hear your apology!
粛清 ろり神レクイエム
Purge, Loli God Requiem!
本当に気持ち悪い
You are really disgusting.
マリンちゃん7周年おめでとー！
Marine-chan, congrats on your 7th anniversary!
じゃ、帰るね！
Well, I'm heading home!
え、はよ！
Wait, already?!
ド・キ・ド・キ・して rouge? 行きますよー！
Excited with rouge? Here we go!
無罪！無罪！美少女無罪！
Not guilty! Not guilty! Pretty girl is not guilty!
マリン！マリン！マリンは無罪！
Marine! Marine! Marine is not guilty!
やっぱりキラキラもっとクラクラ
After all, sparkling makes you dizzy!
うい！うい！おいういが無罪！
Ui! Ui! Ui is not guilty!
ねぇ、言ったよね？ 年齢なんて関係ないってさ！ そういう面倒くさいのも含めて愛してくれるって！
Hey, you said it, right? That age doesn't matter! That you'd love me including all that troublesome stuff!
ねぇねぇ、言ったよね？ 言ってない？
Hey, hey, you said it, right? Didn't say it?
ふーん、そういうこと言うんだ。ちなみにこの船では美少女無罪が適用されますけど？
Hmm, so that's what you're saying. By the way, on this ship, "Pretty Girl Not Guilty" applies, though?
まかせて！魔法で若返り
Leave it to me! Rejuvenating with magic!
ヒミツの素顔はキミにだけ トクベツですよ〜？
My secret unedited face is just for you, special, you know~?
…アタシ厄介よ
...I'm trouble, you know.
…港なんかじゃ
...In ports like these,
はしゃげないわ近頃はね
I can't fool around lately, you see.
宝の島にしてほしい気分
I feel like wanting it to be a treasure island!
キュートは正義 美少女無罪 キミの一番目指してヨーソロー！
Cute is justice, pretty girl is not guilty! Aiming to be your number one, anchors aweigh!
本当は自信ないけど頑張っちゃう
Honestly, I lack confidence, but I'll do my best!
きゅっきゅっきゅるん きゅっきゅっきゅるんるん
Kyu-kyu-kyurun, kyu-kyu-kyurunrun!
恋する気持ち17歳
In-love feelings, 17 years old!
0時になっちゃうわ オトナの時間
It's turning midnight, adults' time!
ド・キ・ド・キ・して rouge?
Excited with rouge?
まだ早い♡
Still too early♡
きゅっ きゅっ きゅるん きゅっ きゅっ きゅるんるん
Kyu kyu kyurun, kyu kyu kyururun
優しくしてね17歳
Be gentle with this 17-year-old
突っ込んで経験値お楽しみちゅー♡
Dive right in and enjoy gaining experience points!
ドキドキして Rouge?
Is your heart pounding in rouge?
あ〜！あ、よろしくっス！
Ah~! Ah, nice to meet ya!
このういの魅力！魔力！不可抗力！
This Ui's charm! Magic! Irresistible force!
──"罪な女"ね？
── A "sinful woman", right?
離さないでつかまっていて
Hold on tight, don't let go,
世界の広さ見せてあげるから！
because I'll show you how vast the world is!
出航ー！！
Set sail!!
キュートは正義 美少女無罪
Cuteness is justice, a pretty girl is not guilty!
キミの一番目指して ヨーソロー！
Aiming to be your number one, full speed ahead!
冗談も大好きだけど真剣よ
I love joking around, but I'm dead serious!
Ahoy!!
きゅっ きゅっ きゅるん きゅっ きゅっ きゅるんるん
Kyu kyu kyurun, kyu kyu kyururun
恋する気持ち17歳
A loving heart, 17 years old
0時になっちゃうわ オトナの時間
It's turning midnight, adult time!
やっぱりキラキラ
Sparkling after all
ドキドキして Rouge?
Is your heart pounding in rouge?
まだ早い♡
Still too early~♡
無罪！無罪！美少女無罪！
Not guilty! Not guilty! Pretty girl is not guilty!
マリン！マリン！マリンは無罪！
Marine! Marine! Marine is not guilty!
無罪！無罪！美少女無罪！
Not guilty! Not guilty! Pretty girl is not guilty!
うい！うい！ういは無罪！
Ui! Ui! Ui is not guilty!
やっぱりキラキラ もっとクラクラ
Sparkling after all, making you dizzier
マリン船長とういちゃんだろ〜うが！
It's Captain Marine and Ui-chan, obviously!
はぁー！はい！
Phew~! Yes!
マリンちゃん！
Marine-chan!
あー！ういちゃん！
Ah~! Ui-chan!
ということで… マリンは…
So then... Marine is...
疲れている… ですが、さすが9歳！元気いっぱいだ！
Tired... But as expected of a 9-year-old! So energetic!
えー？ ちょっと無理してる？
Eh? Pushing yourself a bit?
はい、マリンの急所…間違えた
Yes, Marine's weak spot... wait, I messed up.
お前も9歳ではない！
You're not 9 years old either!
そうです！マリンの7周年ライブに、じゃん！ういちゃんが来てくれました！
That's right! For Marine's 7th anniversary live, ta-da! Ui-chan came to join us!
イエーイ！お邪魔しまーす！おめでとう！
Yay! Thanks for having me! Congratulations!
ありがとうございまーす！
Thank you so much!
なんとね、マリンね、16歳のういとはね、
Actually, Marine and 16-year-old Ui...
まあもう、めっちゃマブ？
Well, are like super besties?
あ、そうなんだ。
Oh, is that so?
なんだのね、ういちゃんともね、これから
You know, with Ui-chan, from now on...
マブになっていきたいなって思ってて、初絡みなんですけど、どうぞよろしく！
I want to become besties, and although this is our first real interaction, nice to meet you!
あ、帰ります。
Oh, I'm going home.
ちょっと待て！ちょっと待てよ！ちょっと待てよ！
Wait a minute! Wait a second! Wait a second!
ということでね！
Anyway!
ういちゃん、何か気づかない？
Ui-chan, notice anything?
え？露出？ あ、すごい。
Huh? Exposure? Oh, wow.
興味ある？興味ある？
Interested? Are you interested?
これね、ういちゃん、あなたの放ったういビームで…
You see, Ui-chan, when you fired your Ui Beam...
バーン！
Bang!
あの、新しい設定付けないでください。
Um, please don't add new lore to me.
ういビームで服が弾け飛んだ。 そんな機能ありません！
My clothes blew off from the Ui Beam. - It doesn't have that function!
ていう感じでね、新衣装となっています。
So yeah, this is my new outfit.
めっちゃ可愛…え、なんかぬいぐるみついてない？
Super cute... wait, isn't there a plushie attached?
欲しい！1個もらっていい？
I want it! Can I have one?
うわ、すごい9歳っぽい！めっちゃ9歳。
Woah, so 9-year-old-like! Very 9-year-old.
いいよ！いいよ、ぶちっ！おっぱいもげる、ぶちっ！
Sure! Sure, *rip*! Tearing off my boob, *rip*!
お土産！じゃあね〜！
A souvenir! See ya~!
ちょっ待てよ！ちょっ待てよ！
Wait up! Wait up!
見て、ほら、ここにさ、ほら、3…
Look, see, right here, see, 3...
あ、本当だ！背中に3…
Oh, it's true! There's a 3 on your back...
お尻すっげ。
Look at that butt.
30じゃないよ！ 3年？
It's not 30! - 3 years?
30じゃないよ！
It's not 30!
いや、ういちゃんね、これね… まだまだ脱げるんで！
Well, Ui-chan, you see... I can take off even more!
大丈夫ですか？
Are you sure that's okay?
この後ね… YouTube的に大丈夫ですか？
After this... - Is that okay for YouTube standards?
髪型とか、服とか、まだまだね、違うのがあるのでね、
Hairstyle, clothes, and more, there are still different versions!
みんなね、これで満足して帰らないように！
So everyone, don't leave thinking you're satisfied with just this!
BANされないように隠してください！
Please cover up so you don't get banned!
まだあるよ！まだまだあるよ！ということで…
There's still more! There's plenty more! So then...
あとね、選曲の話もしようと思うんですけど、
Also, I wanted to talk about the song selection, but...
えっと、ういちゃんとは…
Um, with Ui-chan...
えー、もうやっぱりね、持ち歌の…
Well, of course, her signature song...
『粛聖☆ロリ神レクイエム☆』
"Shukusei ☆ Loli-kami Requiem ☆"
やりましたけど、かわちー！ どうでしたか？
We performed it, so cute~! - How was it?
えっとね、マリン歌ってみたも出してるんですけど、
Well, Marine also released a "Sang It" cover of it, but...
球体のやつね！
The one with the sphere, right!
そう！マリンの歌ってみたバージョンだとめっちゃ「レクイエム！！」って感じので歌ってたんだけど、
Yeah! In Marine's cover version, I sang it with a super intense "REQUIEM!!" vibe,
何て？
What?
「レクイエム！！！」って感じで… ひねり出してたんだけど、
Like "REQUIEM!!!"... I was squeezing it out like that, but...
まあ今回はね、マリンもこの姿のまま「レクイエム！」って言ったらちょっとあっ…てなるから、
But this time, if Marine shouted "REQUIEM!" looking like this, it would be a bit... awkward,
言ってるね、もう今ね。
You're saying it right now though.
ここはちょっと真面目にね、普通にいつものマリンで歌わせてもらいました。
So here, I stayed a bit serious, singing as the usual Marine.
そっちの方があいいよ！マリンちゃん！
That way is much better, Marine-chan!
なんだよ！なんだよ！
What's that supposed to mean?!
深刻ぶらない方がいいよ。 何てー？！
You shouldn't try to act so grim. - What did you say?!
やめてー！
Stop it~!
あとは、あの、ういの方とはね、K-Arenaでういのライブで一緒に歌わせてもらった…
Also, on Ui's side... when we sang together at Ui's live at K-Arena...
やってたのにね！
Even though we did that!
歌いましたので！ 疲れた…
We sang it! - I'm tired...
疲れた？疲れたね。いいよ、もう帰って。疲れたでしょ？
Tired? You're tired. It's fine, go on home. You're tired, right?
じゃあ帰ります。 話終わったから。
Okay, I'm going home then. - Since we're done talking.
まだまだライブは続くぞ！
The live show is still continuing!
冷たい！
Cold!
まだまだ続く！ ひどい！
It continues! - Terrible!
Let's Go! バイバーイ！
Let's Go! - Bye-bye~!
お、応援してろ！
N-now go cheer for me!
こんなに求められてないゲストいる？
Is there any guest who is this unwanted?
Parade! Parade! Parade!
輝くんだよ
Shine bright
呼び合う声を合図に
With our calling voices as the signal
Parade! Parade! Parade!
探しにゆく
Going to search for it
スタートは何度だって
No matter how many times we start anew
手をあげて Clap your hands 海の向こうまで
Raise your hands, clap your hands, to the other side of the ocean
Clap your hands 届きますように
Clap your hands, so that it reaches far away
ドタバタコ ドタバタコ
Dotabatako, dotabatako!
ほら一緒に Everybody clap your hands!
Come on, together, everybody clap your hands!
空の向こうまで Clap your hands
To the other side of the sky, clap your hands
響きますように
So that it resounds
ドタバタコ ドタバタコ
Dotabatako, dotabatako!
光差す 僕たちの未来
The light shining on our future
Are you ready?
KON KON KON Yes! こんな狐に騙されて
KON KON KON Yes! Getting tricked by a fox like me
Knock knock knock 心を開けて
Knock knock knock, open up your heart
Yeah, everything's gonna be alright
感じよう 今 噂の Feeling with you
Let's feel it now, that rumored feeling with you
もう一回！
One more time!
KON KON KON Yes!
こんな狐に騙されて
Getting tricked by a fox like me
Knock knock knock
心を開けて
Open up your heart
Turn up the music ほら明日まで行くよ
Turn up the music, going all the way until tomorrow
今 地球の裏に Tuning
Tuning to the other side of the Earth right now
KON KON KON 魔法をかけて 狐色の夢を見る
KON KON KON, casting a spell to dream a fox-colored dream
ねぇもっと好きになってもらいたいのお
Hey, I want you to like me even more
頭の中は君ばっかって言わせたい
I want to make you say your head is full of me
ぼーっとなんて向いてないで
Don't stare off into space like that
あーもう 浮気しちゃうわ
Ah geez, I'm gonna cheat on you!
ずっとずっと好きがいいの
I want you to love me forever and ever
心の奥まで決め打ち頂戴
Commit to me deep down in your heart
こっち向いててよ 他に
Look over here at me, don't look anywhere else
あもう離さないから
Ah, I won't ever let you go
絶対に I love you
Definitely, I love you!
It's 1:00 AM, 2:00 AM, 3:00 AM, 4:00 AM
Driving 走る高速道路
Driving along the highway
あたしを大変身させてよ
Give me a complete transformation!
ズラッと並んで Dancing
Dancing lined up in a row
サヨナラ Good-bye Let's go
Goodbye, farewell, let me go
ビビッと喝采クラスの Audience
An audience brimming with applause
皆様 ご唱和あれ
Everyone, sing along!
Bibbidi-Bobbidi-Boo-wah! Bibbidi-Bobbidi-Boo-wah!
ほら脱ぎ散らかしてもしょうがない
Leaving your shoes strewn about won't help
Bibbidi-Bobbidi-Boo-wah! Bibbidi-Bobbidi-Boo-wah!
いやいや明日となんのなら 12時踊っても問題ないでしょ
No way, if tomorrow isn't coming, dancing past midnight is no problem, right?
失礼しますが死んでください！
Excuse my rudeness, but could you please RIP?!
Fill 'em with the bass! ほら、そこの方が楽しい！
Fill 'em with the bass! See, isn't that more fun?!
Die, bitch! まだ It's so fucking かわいい
Die, bitch! But you're still so fucking cute!
かわいいね
So cute, right?
シニガミ Sensei, carpe diem! Fill 'em with the bass, together we say
Shinigami Sensei, carpe diem! Fill 'em with the bass, together we say
刺激的な Answer
An exciting answer!
So dose, deadbeats, listen up! It's what you wanted, isn't it?
勝手にやってる地獄で 犯罪じゃないから
Doing our own thing in Hell, it's not a crime!
絶叫! You can check in, but you can never check out!
Scream! You can check in, but you can never check out!
困ったのなら なんとなく一緒に楽しもう
If you're troubled, let me just enjoy it together with you
あなたの死因は？
What's your cause of death?
申し訳ないです やりすぎました なんて？ 筋トレラップしてる？ ちょっと変だ！
I'm so sorry, I overdid it! What? Doing a workout rap? That's kinda weird!
一切合切お任せあれ Doggy, doggy god
Leave absolutely everything to us, Doggy, doggy god
You can go bye-bye, bye-bye, baby, Doggy, doggy god
挑戦状の疾風怒濤 Doggy, doggy god
A stormy tempest of challenges, Doggy, doggy god
Clap your hands, wag your tail, on and on and on
Bow-wow-wow, love or die! 狂乱のままさ
Bow-wow-wow, love or die! Wildly frenzied as ever
パワフルにバタバタするんだ この奇跡のファンファーレ
Bustling around powerfully in this miraculous fanfare
放さない ワンチャンスで輝け
Don't let go, shine in this single chance
絶対的ヒメゴト 僕らの Doggy god
An absolute secret, our Doggy god
あー 骨頂高架下のレストランで
Ah, at a top-tier underpass restaurant
ウソパチのメニューにお茶こぼして
Spilling tea over a fake menu
君と もぐもぐ もぐもぐ
Mogu mogu, mogu mogu with you
超激戦の真ん中で もぐもぐ
Mogu mogu right in the middle of a super fierce battle
身の丈払って この群れ 満足になり
Paying our fair share, this pack becomes satisfied
未来を願っているよ もぐもぐ
Wishing for the future, mogu mogu
もぐもぐ もぐもぐ 世界が終わる前に
Mogu mogu, mogu mogu before the world ends
Mogu mogu YUMMY! Magical
Yum yum ありのまま
Yum yum, just as we are
Mogu mogu YUMMY! Magical
この世を味わうんだ ウマウマ
Savoring this world, yummy yummy
セクシー世界一 スーパービッチ
World's #1 sexiest super bitch!
ピチピチ
Super peachy peachy!
ぶっちゃけ船長捕まえ合いたくない？
Honestly, don't you want to capture Senchou?
You're gonna get the treasure
Maybe tasting me
私の甘さが 欲しいでしょ
You want my sweetness, don't you?
秘宝の鍵を
The key to the treasure,
優しく刺して
gently insert it,
宝庫の扉
and open the door to the treasure chest...
マジで早く開けて
Seriously, hurry up and open it!
Ahoy!
自覚ないでしょうね 思い通りに
You're probably unaware that, as intended,
君は動かされていること
you are being manipulated.
単純じゃないの 駆け引きの意図は
The intent behind this bargaining isn't simple.
すべてシナリオ
It's all a script.
唯一無二の女帝が演じることで
By having the one and only empress perform it,
理解できた愛の形も
even the form of love you came to understand
どこかの誰かに仕組まれていて
was set up by someone somewhere.
疑問を持っても
Even if you have doubts,
最後に笑う君の
of you who laughs in the end,
加速していく
accelerating...
見せていること
showing it...
最終選別へのステージへ
To the stage for the final selection!
憧れの舞台立ちたい
I want to stand on the stage of my dreams,
らしさ輝きたい
I want to shine as myself,
時に涙して
crying sometimes,
また笑い合いたい
and laughing together again.
同じ未来を見たい
I want to see the same future,
あの夢手にしたい
I want to hold that dream in my hands,
踏み出そう 奇跡の一歩を
Let's take a miraculous step forward!
息切らして夢追いかけたい
Out of breath, I want to chase my dreams,
ワクワク止まらない
the excitement never stops,
想像越えてく
surpassing imagination,
世界見せてあげる
I'll show you a whole new world!
アクセスしてみたい？
Want to try accessing it?
後悔なんてここにない
There are no regrets here!
それぞれ違ったココロで
With our different hearts,
作る world
creating a world!
ハイ注目！
Attention, please!
視線集中してんのは あ、あ、アイ
All eyes are locked on l-l-love.
あれ？君たちの声、まだ足りてないんじゃないのー？
Huh? Your voices aren't loud enough yet, are they?
All right, just got a last blast dance
熱く火照る体
A body burning hot,
人は知っちゃってるのさ 乾いた喉潤す
people already know how to quench a dry throat.
オアシスちょうだい
Give me an oasis!
たまらないんだろう
You can't resist it, can you?
From shore to shore, I'm gonna get you wet on the dance floor
Taking over LA, Mia to New York
Step to the rhythm and you ready for more?
You wanna bump my shine, look at you, so divine
I can make it rain when I hit the jackpot, baby
Get ready if you wanna ride on with all day
感じなくなるわ 誰
Who will make me stop feeling?
目眩ましあげた苗
A seedling raised as an illusion...
目移りしちゃうような
So dazzling you can't look away,
All right, just got a last blast dance
感じて激しくなれ
Feel it and get intense!
来世まで魅了の奴隷
A slave to fascination until the next life.
Oh my, ゾッコン合い 目指してハイアー
Oh my, head over heels, aim higher!
エイマ、まだまだ湧いてこうぜ
Hey now, let's keep getting hyped!
ハイ注目！ 視線集中してんのは
Attention, please! All eyes are locked on...
あ、あ、アイ
l-l-love.
She got the body, let me show what's all about
華奢なこの体
She got the body, let me show what's all about.
This delicate body,
どこ探してもいねぇ原宿 増す増す感度
nowhere to be found in Harajuku, sensitivity rising higher and higher.
見つめ見つめ合ったら Good-bye to pink high side
Coloring the ever so cute
When our eyes meet, good-bye to pink high side,
coloring the ever so cute.
Bringin' the heat, the town is miles away
Preaching a bit, can't stop, don't hide
Is standard? I'm just chillin'
Pour the champagne, I'm sippin' cuz I can't let you lose
No way, I let you have a taste
この体で Let me look at your body
With this body, let me look at your body.
光る素肌に
On glowing bare skin,
Set the phone on fire, alluring song they do have
We got you crazy
熱く激しくなってこう！
Let's get hot and wild!
もっと頂戴
Give me more!
はーい 注目
Attention, please!
まあ いっちょ
Well then, shall we...
踊ってこうか？
...dance a bit?
視線牛耳ってんのは…
Controlling your gaze is...
III
アーッ チチな二人ハだぁれ？
Who are these two hot babes?
Hands up ぶち上げたまえ！
Hands up, raise the hype!
クラッときちゃうような
The heat that makes you dizzy...
熱が足りない
...isn't enough!
Our nights just begun, aye let's blast it!
ハジけて派手にいったーれ！
Go wild and blow it up in style!
来世まで we wanna party
We wanna party until the next life!
All eyes on me, I can taste the high
Aye まだばかり沸いてこうぜ
Aye, let's get hyped up even more!
はーい 注目
Attention, please!
まあ いっちょ
Well then, shall we...
踊ってこうか？
...dance a bit?
視線牛耳ってんのは…
Controlling your gaze is...
III
はーい 注目
Attention, please!
まあ いっちょ
Well then, shall we...
踊ってこうか？
...dance a bit?
視線牛耳ってんのは…
Controlling your gaze is...
III
これ
Hey!
君たちの声 まだ足りてないんじゃないの？
Aren't your voices still not loud enough?
Our nights just begun, aye let's blast it!
赤く火照る face
Red, flushing face
ヒートアップしちゃって light up the place
Heating up, light up the place!
渇いた喉潤すオアシス さあマリンブルー
An oasis to quench your thirsty throat, come on, Marine Blue!
Ah-ha! たまらないんだろ？
Ah-ha! You can't resist it, right?
From shore to shore
I'm gonna get your ass on the dance floor
We're taking over L.A., Miami, New York
Step to the rhythm and you're ready for more
If you wanna block my shine? Go get your sunblock
I can make it rain when I hit the jackpot
Baby, get ready
If you wanna ride on with the OGs, all day
アーッ チチな二人ハだぁれ？
Who are these two hot babes?
Hands up ぶち上げたまえ！
Hands up, raise the hype!
クラッときちゃうような
The heat that makes you dizzy...
熱が足りない
...isn't enough!
Our nights just begun, aye let's blast it!
ハジけて派手にいったーれ！
Go wild and blow it up in style!
来世まで we wanna party
We wanna party until the next life!
All eyes on me, I can taste the high
Aye まだばかり沸いてこうぜ
Aye, let's get hyped up even more!
はーい 注目
Attention, please!
まあ いっちょ
Well then, shall we...
踊ってこうか？
...dance a bit?
視線牛耳ってんのは…
Controlling your gaze is...
III
She got the gyatt, now let me see you work with all of that
Can you call a doctor 'cause this baddie's giving me a heart attack
But you know what's scary to me?
Holo make girls look like Halle Berry to me
I'm two bars from being cancelled
So I gotta leave you ever so carefully
Bring in the heat that can't be splashed away
Fishing a big catch, the stardom I deserve
But I'm just chilling, Courvoisier I'm sipping
'Cause I got that juice and I might let you have a taste
この身体で Let me rock your body
With this body, let me rock your body
秘宝な素肌に Now put that camera on me
On my treasure-like skin, now put that camera on me
Beside a bonfire
Our luring smoke takes you higher
ね？ We drive you crazy
Right? We drive you crazy
熱く激しくなってこう
Let's get hot and passionate!
もう どうしようもない
There's no stopping us now!
はーい 注目
Attention, please!
まあ いっちょ
Well then, shall we...
踊ってこうか？
...dance a bit?
視線牛耳ってんのは…
Controlling your gaze is...
III
アーッ チチな二人ハだぁれ？
Who are these two hot babes?
Hands up ぶち上げたまえ！
Hands up, raise the hype!
クラッときちゃうような
The heat that makes you dizzy...
熱が足りない
...isn't enough!
Our nights just begun, aye let's blast it!
ハジけて派手にいったーれ！
Go wild and blow it up in style!
来世まで we wanna party
We wanna party until the next life!
All eyes on me, I can taste the high
Aye まだばかり沸いてこうぜ
Aye, let's get hyped up even more!
はーい 注目
Attention, please!
まあ いっちょ
Well then, shall we...
踊ってこうか？
...dance a bit?
視線牛耳ってんのは…
Controlling your gaze is...
III
俺らさぁ マジで最強じゃん？
Aren't we seriously the strongest?
Just two besties so fly!
IRIS OUT
[Song Title: IRIS OUT]
駄目駄目駄目 脳みその中から
No, no, no! From inside my brain...
「やめろ馬鹿」と喚くモラリティ
...morality screams, "Stop it, you fool!"
ダーリン ベイビー ダーリン 半端なくラブ！
Darling, baby, darling, crazy love!
ときめき浮き足立つフィロソフィー
A heart-throbbing, restless philosophy.
死ぬほど可愛い上目遣い
That upward glance is deadly cute,
なにがし法に触れるくらい
...almost breaking some kind of law.
ばら撒く乱心 気づけば蕩尽
Scattering madness, bankrupt before I know it—
この世に生まれた君が悪い
...it's your fault for being born into this world!
やたらとしんどい恋煩い
This lovesickness is painfully intense,
バラバラになる頭とこの身体
...tearing my mind and body to pieces.
頸動脈からアイラブユーが吹き出て
"I love you" gushes out from my carotid artery,
アイリスアウト
...and iris out.
今この世で君だけ大正解
In this world right now, only you are the absolute right answer.
誰？ 誰？ 誰？ 誰？ 誰？ 誰？ 誰？ 誰？
Who? Who? Who? Who? Who? Who? Who? Who?
ひっくり返しても価値もない
Even if turned upside down, it's worthless.
君だけルール外で提供外
You alone are outside the rules and non-refundable.
殺しても面白くはない 殺し方切り分け放題
Even if killed, it's not interesting. All-you-can-slice killing methods.
申し訳ねえな
My apologies.
酔わさせて
Get me drunk,
突き抜いて
pierce right through,
ここ弱点？
is this the weak point?
死ぬほど可愛いお前につける薬が死のふち触れるくらい
The medicine applied to you, who is deadly cute, almost touches the edge of death.
腹まくらシンと静めば 当人この世に生まれた君が悪い
When resting on a lap pillow quietly, it's your fault for being born into this world.
パチモンでもいい何でもいい 今君と抱きついてるすべて欲しい
Fake or whatever, anything is fine. I want everything that's clinging to you right now.
頸動脈からアイラブユーが噴き出して
"I love you" gushes out from the carotid artery...
アイリスアウト
IRIS OUT
一体どうしよう この想いをどうしよう
What on earth should I do? What should I do with these feelings?
アバラの奥を
Deep inside my ribs...
その目が溶けて泥になりそう
Those eyes seem about to melt into mud.
堂々 パチ開いておこぼれちりそう
Snapping wide open, about to spill over.
今この世で君だけ大正解
In this world right now, only you are the absolute right answer.
ダーリン ダーリン ダーリン ダーリン！
Darling! Darling! Darling! Darling!
改めて
Once again,
おめでとう！ ありがとう！
Congratulations! Thank you!
イエーイ！ ハッピーアニバーサリー！
Yay! Happy anniversary!
7周年の...
Happy 7th Anniversary...
かわちぃ！ かわちぃ！
So cute! So cute!
ちょっと服似てるよ、ほら。ね、似てるね。
Our outfits look a bit similar, see? They match.
うん、うん、似てる？
Yeah, yeah, do they?
似てるよー！ほら、フ... あ、これフード。
They match~! Look, the hoo... Ah, this is a hood.
フード。
A hood.
こぼもフードありますよ。
Kobo has a hood too!
え？これ？どれ？
Huh? This? Which one?
どこや？
Where is it?
埋まってる！
It's buried!
被れないだろ、それ！
You can't even put that on!
うわ、かわちぃねー。
Aww, so cute!
え、どこー？どこが可愛い？
Eh, where? What part is cute?
めっちゃセクシー！なんか、スイムスーツでしょ？
Super sexy! Like, it's a swimsuit, right?
そう、スイムスーツ。
Yeah, a swimsuit.
あーセクシー！水着可愛い！こぼも...
Ah, sexy! The swimsuit is cute! Kobo also...
このスイムスーツ欲しい！
wants a swimsuit like this!
あ、欲しい？
Ah, you want one?
うん、なんかこぼはー、リボン好き。
Yeah, Kobo likes ribbons.
あ、リボン？どのリボン？
Ah, ribbons? Which ribbon?
この、見、あー...
This, look, ah...
リボンはこれ！小さいけど...
This ribbon! It's small, but...
あ、ちっちゃいリボン？ちっちゃいリボン。
Ah, the tiny ribbon? The tiny ribbon.
あ、見え... あ、見えた見えた。
Ah, see... Ah, I see it, I see it.
綺麗！すごい！
Pretty! Awesome!
あ、こっちも！
Ah, this side too!
そうそうそう、これ！めっちゃ可愛い！このリボンが...
Yeah yeah yeah, this! Super cute! This ribbon...
うわー！あー！
Wow~! Ah~!
待って、リボンとお尻どっちが可愛い？
Wait, which is cuter, the ribbon or my butt?
おい！おい！助かる！
Hey! Hey! What a blessing!
こぼもっとさ、脱いでるの見たいでしょ？
Kobo, you want to see me take off more, right?
あ、あのこれ...
Ah, like this...
え、ダメだよ！
Eh, you shouldn't!
脱いでくる！
I'm gonna strip down!
見せてあげる、こぼ。
I'll show you, Kobo.
大丈夫ですか？
Is that really okay?
楽しみに待ってて。
Look forward to it!
やっべー！
Oh crap!
こぼ見て！
Kobo, look!
やっべー！
Oh crap!
うわー！セクシーレディー！
Wow! Sexy lady!
ちる！
Chill!
服着るわ、服着る。
I'll put my clothes back on.
やっべー、BANされないようにね。
Crap, make sure we don't get banned!
やっべー、子供... 子供見ないで！
Oh crap, kids... Kids, don't look!
あ、もう着た、もう着た。ほら、じゃーん！
Ah, I put it back on! Ta-da!
あー！すごい！
Ah~! Amazing!
これセーフ、セーフ！
This is safe, safe!
セーフ！
Safe!
で、今日はね、
And today, you see,
あの『IRIS OUT』のね、
we covered "IRIS OUT"!
楽しかった！
It was so fun!
あ、マリンお尻...
Ah, Marine's butt...
Today, I I I...
Today, IRIS...
IRIS OUT, Western version!
すごいカッコいいバージョンになった曲をカバーさせてもらいました！
We got to cover a super cool version of the song!
カッコいいバージョンありがとうございます！
Thank you for the cool version!
Great job with the cover! マリンの英語のラップどうだった？
Great job with the cover! How was Marine's English rap?
シー ガッタ ゲット、ナウ レット ミー シー ユー ワーク ウィズ オール オブ ザット！
She got to get, now let me see you work with all of that!
She got to get!
Get! Get!
Yeah!
Now let me see you work with all of that!
上手！
So good!
Now let me see you work with all of that!
て、何？
Wait, what?
Now let me see you work with all of that!
それは英語ですか？
Is that English?
英語です！
It's English!
マリグリッシュです！
It's Maringlish!
Can you call a doctor?
Call this body, give me a holler!
頑張ったなー！
You did great~!
えらいえらい！頑張ったなー！
Good job, good job! You did great~!
英語...
English...
英語、うん、頑張ったー！
English, yep, you tried your best!
イェーイ！
Yay!
続きますので
There's still more to come,
ぜひ見ていってください！
so please stay tuned and watch!
はーい！ありがとうございました！
Yes! Thank you so much!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
乗ってる… あ、うわ！
You're on top of me... Ah, woah!
うわー！重っ！
Woah! You're heavy!
痛った！
Ouch!
死んだ… 死んだ… 死んだ…
I'm dead... Dead... Dead...
お別れしたのはもっと 前のことだったような
It feels like it was a long time ago that we said goodbye
悲しい光は封じ込めて かかとすり減らしたんだ
Keeping the sad light locked away, I wore down my heels
君といた時は見えた 今は見えなくなった
I could see it when I was with you, but now I can't anymore
透明な彗星をぼんやりと でもそれだけ探している
I'm vaguely searching for a transparent comet, but that's all I look for
しょっちゅう唄を歌ったよ その時だけのメロディーを
I often sang songs, melodies that existed only in those moments
寂しくなんかなかったよ ちゃんと寂しくなれたから
I wasn't lonely, because I was truly able to feel the loneliness
いつまでどこまでなんて
Asking how long or how far
正常か異常かなんて
Or whether this is normal or abnormal
考える暇も無い程 歩くのは大変だ
Walking is so tough I don't even have time to think about it
楽しい方がずっといいよ
Having fun is so much better
ごまかして笑っていくよ
I'll fake it and keep on smiling
大丈夫だ あの痛みの 忘れたって消えやしない
It's okay, that pain won't fade even if I forget it
理想で作った道を 現実が塗り替えていくよ
Reality paints over the path we paved with our ideals
思い出はその軌跡の上で 輝きになって残っている
On that trail, memories remain as a shining light
お別れしたのは何で 何のためだったんだろうな
Why did we say goodbye? What was it all for, I wonder?
悲しい光が僕の影を 前に長く伸ばしている
A sad light stretches my shadow long out in front of me
時々熱があるよ
Sometimes I run a fever
時間がある時眠るよ
I sleep whenever I have the time
夢だと解るその中で 君と会ってからまた行こう
Knowing it's a dream, I'll meet you inside and keep going
晴天とはほど遠い
Far from a clear sky
終わらない暗闇にも
Even in this endless darkness
星を思い浮かべたなら すぐ銀河の中だ
If you picture the stars, you're right inside the galaxy
あまり泣かなくなっても
Even if I don't cry much anymore
靴を新しくしても
Even if I put on new shoes
大丈夫だ あの痛みの 忘れたって消えやしない
It's okay, that pain won't fade even if I forget it
伝えたい事が きっとあったんだろな
There must have been something I wanted to tell you
恐らくありきたりなんだろうけど こんなにも
It was probably something cliché, but even so
お別れした事は 出会った事と繋がっている
Saying goodbye is connected to having met you
あの透明な彗星は 透明だから無くならない
That transparent comet will never disappear because it's transparent
○×どれかなんて
Right or wrong, whichever it is
皆と比べてどうかなんて
Comparing myself with everyone else
確かめる間も無い程 生きるの最高だ
Being alive is so great I don't even have time to check
あまり泣かなくなっても
Even if I don't cry much anymore
ごまかして笑っていくよ
I'll fake it and keep on smiling
大丈夫だ あの痛みの 忘れたって消えやしない
It's okay, that pain won't fade even if I forget it
大丈夫だ この光の始まりには
It's okay, at the origin of this light...
君がいる
...you are there
朝起きて今日は何しよう
What should I do today when I wake up?
好奇心抑えられない
I can't suppress my curiosity.
踊り出すハートは制御不可能
My dancing heart is uncontrollable.
テンプレートは丸めて捨てて
Crumple up the templates and throw them away,
スキップで踏みつけちゃおう
and let's trample over them with a skip!
地球全部塗り替えちゃおう
Let's repaint the entire Earth!
カチコチはだるいしマジ無理！
Being stiff is annoying and totally impossible!
そんなんソッコーイチ抜け！
I'm backing out of that right away!
あっかんべーなんだが
Sticking my tongue out at you,
上等！
Bring it on!
心拍数上げて生きようよ
Let's live raising our heart rate!
退屈奪っていこうよ
Let's snatch away boredom!
ウザいのも沼って好きになっちゃうよ☆
Even annoying things will become addicting and lovable!
完璧キャラ無理ゲー知らんぶり
Pretending not to care about playing a perfect character,
可愛すぎてグランプリ
winning the grand prix for being too cute!
Ah 何でも知りたい味見したい
Ah, I want to know everything, I want to taste it all!
誰も止められやしない
No one can stop me!
歌わずにはいられない
I can't help but sing!
もしもで諦めるより
Rather than giving up on "what ifs",
もしもでBETかましたい
I want to bet on those "what ifs"!
この世界知らない方が損じゃん？
Isn't it a loss if you don't know this world?
疲れたらちょっとサボって
When you're tired, slack off a bit,
糖分で回復して
recover with some sweets,
自分のご機嫌取ろう♪
and cheer yourself up♪
優等生演じてても無理！
Pretending to be an honor student is impossible!
ナチュラルで愛らしい乙女なんだが
I'm just a naturally cute maiden, but...
最強！
I'm the strongest!
大好き囲まれて生きようよ
Let's live surrounded by things we love!
明日も笑っていたいよ
I want to be laughing tomorrow, too!
知っちゃったらそのまま好きになっちゃうぞ☆
Once you know, you'll fall in love just like that!
妄想突破無限上げてくし
Breaking through fantasies endlessly,
頂点にだって連れてくし
and taking you all the way to the top!
Ah いつでも無茶より攻めの姿勢
Ah, always aiming aggressively rather than recklessly!
誰も止められやしない
No one can stop me!
踊らずにはいられない
I can't help but dance!
下向いているそこの君
You over there, looking down,
不満ばかりこぼしても意味ないじゃんバカ！
Complaining endlessly is useless, dummy!
リセットは無し一度きり
No resets, life is only once,
いつでも真剣勝負ギリ
Always playing for keeps on the edge!
もっともっともっともっともっと ワガママになろうぜ！君の人生☆
Let's get more and more selfish! It's your life!
我慢とかしなくていい
You don't have to hold back.
そばにいる
I'm right beside you.
今もこれからもずっと
Now, and forever and ever,
約束！
I promise!
心拍数上げて生きようよ
Let's live raising our heart rate!
退屈奪っていこうよ
Let's snatch away boredom!
ウザいのも沼って好きになっちゃうよ☆
Even annoying things will become addicting and lovable!
完璧キャラ無理ゲー知らんぶり
Pretending not to care about playing a perfect character,
可愛すぎてグランプリ
winning the grand prix for being too cute!
Ah 何でも知りたい味見したい
Ah, I want to know everything, I want to taste it all!
誰も止められやしない
No one can stop me!
歌わずにはいられない
I can't help but sing!
コンプレックス♡プリンセス
Complex Princess♡
La La La La La La La
一瞬記憶が錯乱するが、恋は恋だ。
For a moment my memory gets confused, but love is love.
お楽しみボディ
Enjoyable body
愛のボランティア 撫でます！ドンッ！！
Volunteer of love, I'll stroke you! Bam!!
どす恋 患い
Deeply in love
圧倒的な母性と
With overwhelming maternal instinct and...
(キミたちー♡)
(You guys♡)
勝手に進む年齢
Age advances on its own
(止められねぇんだよ！)
(Can't stop it!)
鳴らない鐘を鳴らしましょう
Let's ring the bell that won't ring
私だけを見てくれますか？
Will you look only at me?
ねぇ♡
Hey♡
好き好き好き好き 片思い
Love love love love, unrequited love
めちゃめちゃめちゃめちゃ描いたフューチャー
The future I envisioned so much
大事に大事にして ダーリン
Treasure me, treasure me, darling
コンプレックスプリンセス
Complex Princess
宜しくお願いします♡♡♡
Please treat me well♡♡♡
コンプレックスプリンセス♡
Complex Princess♡
La La La La La La La
コンプレックスプリンセス♡
Complex Princess♡
La La La La La La La
SEXY＆CUTE 全部見せたい 今会いたい♡
SEXY & CUTE, I want to show you everything, I want to see you now♡
(ようこそ！マリンワールドへ！！)
(Welcome to Marine World!!)
運命共同体 一心同体 側にいたい♡
Bound by fate, two bodies as one, I want to be by your side♡
(流石に寂しいわ！愛されたい！！)
(As expected, I'm lonely! I want to be loved!!)
恋愛 不器用 まである
Even clumsy at romance
(脈なしボンバー)
(No chance bomber)
ぶっちゃけ 嫉妬の 申し子
Frankly, the child of jealousy
(膝から崩れ落ちる)
(Collapsing to my knees)
ずっと17歳 もっと愛しなさい
Forever 17, love me more
夢が大きくて ごめんなさい！
Sorry for having such big dreams!
ホラ♡
Look♡
好き好き好き好き 気付いて
Love love love love, notice me
てぇてぇ絆を思い出して
Remember our wholesome bond
熱々 圧力 女子力
Piping hot pressure, girl power
自己肯定低い お姫様♡
Self-deprecating princess♡
お迎えに来て 王子様♡
Come pick me up, prince charming♡
Ah~ 時には ヘル時もあるけど
Ah~ Sometimes I get down too, but...
シナジー全開 海より深い恋心 認知して！
Synergy at full power, acknowledge this love deeper than the sea!
(聞こえておりますでしょうかー！？)
(Can you hear me!?)
Ahoy!!
ヨーソロー！
Yosoro!
出航！！
Set sail!!
ねーえー♡
Hey~♡
好き好き好き好き 片思い
Love love love love, unrequited love
めちゃめちゃめちゃめちゃ描いたフューチャー
The future I envisioned so much
大事に大事にして ダーリン
Treasure me, treasure me, darling
コンプレックスプリンセス
Complex Princess
キミを幸せにします♡♡♡
I'll make you happy♡♡♡
コンプリートプリンセス♡
Complete Princess♡
恋する乙女
A maiden in love
コンプリートプリンセス♡
Complete Princess♡
生まれ変わるの
Reborn anew
キミのプリンセス♡
Your princess♡
というわけで なんと！ツキヨミで大人気のかぐやさんに来ていただきました！
So then, amazingly! We have Kaguya-san, who is super popular in Tsukiyomi, joining us today!
イェーイ！かぐやー！かぐやだよー！
Yay! It's Kaguya~!
うわー！可愛いー！可愛いデス！イェーイ！
Wow! So cute! So cute! Yay!
ところでですね、初絡みなのでお互いの呼び方とか決めたいんですけど
By the way, since this is our first time interacting, I'd like to decide what we should call each other...
おっちょっとね、かぐやは...かぐやで！あ、かぐやでね！
Oh, wait a second. Kaguya is... Kaguya! Ah, Kaguya then!
じゃあマリンのことはマリンでもいいし船長でもいいんですけど、まあ何でもオッケーで
Right! So for me, you can call me Marine or Captain, anything is fine!
じゃあ...マリンって呼ぶね！
Then... I'll call you Marine!
食らった！
That hit me right in the heart!
呼ぶね！
I'll call you that!
食らえ！キャー可愛い！
Take this! Eek, so cute!
あー最高だー！マリンって呼んでくれてありがとう！ありがとうございます！
Ah, that's the best! Thanks for calling me Marine! Thank you so much!
すっごいよこんな大きくて素敵なステージで歌えてさ！もうテンションも爆上がりって感じ！超楽しかった！
It's amazing to sing on such a huge and wonderful stage! My energy is through the roof! It was so much fun!
あ、良かったですー！
Ah, I'm glad!
てさ、マリンは活動7周年なんだよね！そうなんです！
And you know, Marine, it's your 7th anniversary of activities, right? That's right!
おめでとう！ありがとうございます！
Congratulations! Thank you so much!
いやー7年ですよ、7年！すげー！いやー、かぐやはまだまだ新人だと思うんですけど
Wow, 7 years! 7 years! Amazing! Well, Kaguya feels like she's still a newcomer, but...
かぐやも末永く7年、いやそれを超える勢いで末永く活動してください！
Please continue your activities for a long time—7 years, or even beyond that!
当たり前じゃない、一生やるぞー！はい、一生やってくれ、かぐやー！
Of course! Let's do this for life! Yes, please do this for life, Kaguya!
マリンも！一生やるぞー！やるぞー！えい！えい！おー！
Marine too! Let's do this for life! Let me hear you! Ei! Ei! Oh!
どういうテンションなんだw
What kind of energy is this? lol
まあ、それは置いておいてですね、今日選曲の話もさせていただきたいと思います！
Well, putting that aside, I'd like to talk about our song choices today!
かぐやのオリジナル曲「私は私のことが好き」とマリンのオリジナル曲「コンプレックス♡プリンセス」をデュエットしました！
We sang a duet of Kaguya's original song "Watashi wa Watashi no Koto ga Suki" and Marine's original song "Complex♡Princess"!
わたしね、このかぐやの感情豊かなね、歌声が大好きで！
I really love Kaguya's emotional singing voice!
もう歌唱力が高いだけじゃなく表現まで凄いに！
Not only is her singing ability great, but her expressiveness is amazing too!
本当に元気の出る曲でした！楽しかったです！
It was such an uplifting song! It was so much fun!
えー嬉しい！かぐやも超上がった！
Aw, I'm so happy! Kaguya got super hyped up too!
お互いのオリ曲を一緒に披露したわけなんですけど、マリンの『コンプレックス・プレイス』を歌ってみてどうでしたか？
We performed each other's original songs together, but how was singing Marine's "Complex Place"?
えー、もうめちゃ楽しかったー！
Oh, it was so much fun!
おー！よかったー！
Oh! I'm so glad!
もう歌もダンスも可愛いしさ、あとコーラスもめちゃくちゃ楽しい！
The song and dance are so cute, and the chorus was super fun!
そう！楽しい！
Right! It's fun!
もうみんなと一体になれる感じがさ、本当にプリンセスにふさわしい曲だったね！
Feeling united with everyone... it was truly a song fit for a princess!
あー、そうそう！プリンセスだからね！
Ah, right! Because you're a princess!
ねー！
Yeah!
ダブルプリンセスですよ、私たち！
We're double princesses!
そうなんですよ！
That's right!
もう本当に可愛い！もう一生推します！
You're so cute! I'll fan over you forever!
きゅん！あー可愛い！可愛すぎる！
Ah, so cute! You're way too cute!
最後に、かぐやから何かマリンのチャンネルの視聴者に向けてのメッセージや告知などありますでしょうか？
Lastly, Kaguya, do you have any messages or announcements for Marine's viewers?
はい！ございます！
Yes, I do!
みんな、マリンとかぐやのコラボステージを見てくれて本当にありがとう！
Everyone, thank you so much for watching Marine and Kaguya's collab stage!
かぐやすっごく楽しかったよ！
Kaguya had so much fun!
次はツクヨミにも遊びに来てね！
Come visit Tsukuyomi next time too!
そして、かぐやも出てる映画『超かぐや姫』が9月18日(金)より4DXなどの特別フォーマットにパワーアップして上映されることが決定したよ！
And the movie "Super Kaguya-hime" featuring Kaguya will return to theaters in upgraded 4DX formats starting Friday, Sept 18!
おー！新衣装！すごーい！可愛い！
Ooh! New outfits! Awesome! So cute!
そうなの！新衣装で撮影したムビチケも売ってるから、みんな絶対買ってね！
That's right! Movie tickets featuring photos in the new outfits are on sale, so be sure to buy them!
えー！買わなきゃ！買わなきゃ！イエイイエイ！
Wow, gotta buy them! Gotta buy them! Yeah yeah!
そして！12月に「ツクヨミ感謝祭」ってイベントでライブやるんだー！
And! In December, we're performing a live show at the "Tsukuyomi Thanksgiving" event!
ライブ来たー！イエーイ！楽しみ！楽しみ！
A live show! Yay! I'm so excited!
みんな絶対楽しいから来てね！よろしくー！
It'll definitely be fun, so everyone please come! Thanks!
いやー、来たこれ！
Wow, this is awesome!
いや本当に今日のステージを見てね、みんなかぐやのパフォーマンスにメロメロになったと思うので、もっと見たい方はぜひ要チェックです！
Everyone who watched today's stage has fallen head over heels for Kaguya, so if you want to see more, check it out!
いやー、もうマリンもね、かぐやの魅力にメロメロですよ、本当に！
Honestly, Marine has fallen head over heels for Kaguya's charm too!
メロメロでちゅ〜！メロメロビーム！
Head over heels~! Head over heels beam!
でもね、マリンのメロメロは...かぐやを娘にしたいっていう、そういうメロメロだから！
But Marine's affection is the kind where I want to make Kaguya my daughter!
えー何ー？娘ー？
Eh, what? Daughter?
娘にしたいけどー！
I want to make you my daughter!
えー、娘に？欲しかったの、娘。イロピーが羨ましいなー！
Eh, daughter? I wanted a daughter. I'm so jealous of Iro-P!
そうだ、イロピーに怒られちゃう！
Oh wait, Iro-P is gonna scold me!
そうだよ、怒られちゃうね。はい、イロピーのものですから我慢します！
Exactly, she'd scold us. Alright, you belong to Iro-P, so I'll restrain myself!
いや本当に、今度はぜひマリンもツクヨミに呼んでください！
But really, next time please invite Marine to Tsukuyomi too!
えー！絶対来てよ！絶対面白いよ！
Eh! You definitely have to come! It'll be so fun!
ねー、また一緒にライブしようね！
Right, let's do a live performance together again!
したいです！本当にしたい！
I want to! I really do!
本当に今日は来てくれてありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for coming today!
こちらこそありがとうございました！
Thank you so much as well!
じゃあまたねー！バイバーイ！
See you again! Bye-bye!
特報
[Special News]
まるでバーバレラ メロメロよ
Just like Barbarella, head over heels
かなりモーレツに ピチピチよん
Fiercely young and lively
でもサンデーマンデーサンデーマンデーサンデーマンデー ソリチュード
But Sunday Monday Sunday Monday Sunday Monday Solitude
I Love ぜんぶ I Love ぜんぶ I Love ぜんぶ Mine
I love it all, I love it all, I love it all Mine
あー もうムリ 終わり 鬱 全然かわいくないし さ
Ah, I can't anymore, it's over, depressed, I'm not cute at all
めんどーくさいよね？ はー 消えたい 消えよ
I'm annoying, right? *Sigh* I wanna vanish, let's vanish
え？ そこがいい？ ウソばっか... いい女？ 本当に？ お宝以上？ そうかな... 最後のヒロイン？ そうかニャー！
Huh? You like that? Liar... A fine woman? Really? Better than treasure? Maybe... The final heroine? I see, meow!
弱気 バイバイ スタコラサッサ
Bye-bye to being weak, off I scurry
そっそっそうかもね そうだよね！ にゃーんか元気になってきた！
Th-Th-That might be true, right! Somehow I'm getting energized!
サンデーマンデーサンデーマンデーサンデーマンデー ソリチュード
Sunday Monday Sunday Monday Sunday Monday Solitude
I Love ぜんぶ I Love ぜんぶ I Love ぜんぶ Mine
I love it all, I love it all, I love it all Mine
私に瞬くたび 鳴り響くSE
Every time I blink, sound effects echo
きゃび
Kyabi
新曲MV このあとプレミア公開
[New Song MV Premiere Following This Stream]
もっとアイドルでいさせてよ
Let me stay an idol a little longer
きゃび (ヤババババ Shake it! Shake it!)
Kyabi (Yababababa Shake it! Shake it!)
ぎゃぎゃぎゃぎゃぎゃぎゃぎゃ...きゃび
Gya-gya-gya-gya-gya-gya-gya... Kyabi
(1 & 2 & 3 & 4) Shake it! Shake it!
ぎゅぎゅぎゅぎゅぎゅぎゅぎゅ...ぎゅるん
Gyu-gyu-gyu-gyu-gyu-gyu-gyu... Gyurun
まるでバーバレラ メロメロよ
Just like Barbarella, head over heels
かなりモーレツに ピチピチよん
Fiercely young and lively
でもサンデーマンデーサンデーマンデーサンデーマンデー ソリチュード
But Sunday Monday Sunday Monday Sunday Monday Solitude
I Love ぜんぶ I Love ぜんぶ I Love ぜんぶ Mine
I love it all, I love it all, I love it all Mine
あー もうムリ 終わり 鬱 全然かわいくないし さ
Ah, I can't anymore, it's over, depressed, I'm not cute at all
めんどーくさいよね？ はー消えたい 消えよ
I'm annoying, right? *Sigh* I wanna vanish, let's vanish
そこがいい？ ウソばっか... いい女？ 本当に？ そうかな〜 そうかニャー
You like that? Liar... A fine woman? Really? Maybe~ I see, meow
弱気 バイバイ スタコラサッサ
Bye-bye to being weak, off I scurry
そっそっそうかもね そうだよね！ にゃーんか元気になってきた！
Th-Th-That might be true, right! Somehow I'm getting energized!
サンデーマンデーサンデーマンデーサンデーマンデー ごめんねキッズ
Sunday Monday Sunday Monday Sunday Monday, sorry kids
I Love ぜんぶ I Love ぜんぶ I Love ぜんぶ
I love all of it, I love all of it, I love all of it
私が瞬くたび 鳴り響く効果音
Every time I blink, sound effects echo
きゃぴ
Kyapi
洗脳してあげる 洗脳してあげる
I'll brainwash you, I'll brainwash you
I'll beat you up! Gonna beat you up!
Forever seventeen
接近して感電中 ズッキュンしてバタンキュー
Getting close and electrified, shot through the heart and knocked out
I'll beat you up! Gonna beat you up!
萌えよSeventeen
Sprout, Seventeen
セクシー×4 破廉恥バンビーナ
Sexy x4, shameless bambina
洗脳してあげる ×××してあげない
I'll brainwash you, I won't xxx you
カワイイ？ 顔がいい？ 気持ちがイイ！
Cute? Cute face? Feels so good!
洗脳シテアゲル アゲル アゲル
I'll brainwash you, give it to you, give it to you
もっとアイドルでいさせてよ
Let me stay an idol longer
きゃぴ
Kyapi
きゃぴきゃぴ
Kyapi kyapi
いくつになっても
No matter how old I get
きゃきゃきゃきゃきゃきゃきゃきゃ……きゃぴ
Kya-kya-kya-kya-kya-kya-kya-kya... kyapi
(1 & 2 & 3 & 4)
Mixer! Mixer!
きゅきゅきゅきゅきゅきゅきゅきゅ……きゅるりん
Kyu-kyu-kyu-kyu-kyu-kyu-kyu-kyu... kyururin
サンデーマンデーサンデーマンデーサンデーマンデー ソリチュード
Sunday Monday Sunday Monday Sunday Monday, solitude
I Love ぜんぶ I Love ぜんぶ I Love ぜんぶ 発散中
I love all of it, I love all of it, releasing I love all of it
なんてったってなんてったってなんてったってヘヴィキュート
After all, after all, after all, heavy cute
I Love ぜんぶ I Love ぜんぶ I Love ぜんぶ 愛異異異
I love all of it, I love all of it, I love all of it, love-love-love
来世も来々世も浮気しちゃダメよ
Don't cheat in the next life, or the life after that
きゃぴ
Kyapi
洗脳してあげる 洗脳してあげる
I'll brainwash you, I'll brainwash you
I'll beat you up! Gonna beat you up!
Forever seventeen
監禁して催眠中 ズッキュンしてLovin' You
Confining you and hypnotizing you, shot through the heart and Lovin' You
I'll beat you up! Gonna beat you up!
萌えよSeventeen
Sprout, Seventeen
セクシー×4 ごめんね マイダーリン
Sexy x4, sorry my darling
洗脳してあげる もういっそ産んであげる
I'll brainwash you, I'd rather even give birth to you
カワイイ？ 顔がいい？ 気持ちがイイ！
Cute? Cute face? Feels so good!
洗脳シテアゲル アゲルッタラ ア・ゲル！
I'll brainwash you, I said I'll give it to you!
もっとI wanna beat you up!
More, I wanna beat you up!
きっと恋するだっちゃ
I'm surely fallin' in love, ya know
ずっとアイドルでいさせてね
Please let me be an idol forever
神様お願い きゃぴ
God, please... kyapi
(ヤバババ 脳Shake it! Shake it!)
Yaba-baba, brain Shake it! Shake it!
きゃぴのび
Kyapi no bi
キミたち！マリンの7周年ライブを見てくれてありがとうございました！
Everyone! Thank you so much for watching Marine's 7th Anniversary Live!
今、お披露目した新曲の『KYAPI』は、配信終了後アニメMVが公開されます！
The anime MV for my new song "KYAPI", which I just unveiled, will be released after the stream!
マリンの考える一味とマリンの関係性とイチャイチャが詰まったMVなので
It's an MV packed with my vision of Marine and Ichimi's relationship and flirting,
いっぱい見て いっぱい一緒にキュンキュンしてほしいです！
so please watch it a lot and get all flustered together with me!
見てるうちに曲が頭から離れなくなります 洗脳させてください！
As you watch, the song won't leave your head. Please let me brainwash you!
続いて 7周年記念グッズのお知らせです！
Next up, announcements for the 7th Anniversary merchandise!
まずは B2タペストリー！
First, the B2 tapestry!
こちらは今回の新衣装の水着姿を あかさあい先生に描き下ろしていただきました！
Akasa Ai-sensei drew this new illustration of me in my swimsuit outfit!
超美しい！肉感がすごい！絶対飾ってくださいね！
It's super beautiful! The fleshiness is amazing! Make sure to hang it up!
続いて 船長描き下ろしのランダムラバーキーホルダー！
Next, random rubber keychains drawn by Sencho!
デフォルメの絵柄を模索して 「これだ！」と思えるデフォルメにたどり着いたので
I was searching for a chibi style, and once I found one that felt just right,
こんな感じで描いてみました！
I drew them like this!
新衣装と まだラバーキーホルダー描いてないなという衣装でまとめてみました！
I put together the new outfit and outfits I hadn't made rubber keychains for yet!
かなり可愛いバランスになったかなって 自信作なので絶対GETしてくださいね！
They came out super cute, so I'm really proud of them! Be sure to get them!
続いてはこちら！ぬいぐるみキーホルダー！
Next is this! Plushie keychain!
今回の新衣装のデザインで ちっちゃくて可愛いぬいぐるみです！
It's a small and cute plushie featuring my new outfit design!
お写真を撮った時に楽し気に見えるように
To make it look cheerful in photos,
めっちゃテンション高い顔に船長が描き下ろしました！
Sencho drew it with a super excited expression!
楽しいひとときのお供にしてね！
Keep it as a companion during fun times!
続いてはこちら！2Way推し事バッグ！
Next up, the 2Way Oshi-Activity Bag!
船長の新衣装の太ももにつけているポーチのデザインとお揃いです！
It matches the design of the pouch on Sencho's thigh in her new outfit!
普段使いしやすく 推し活の時には推し活仕様にできるというところを意識しました！
I made sure it's easy for daily use, but can switch to fan-mode for fan events!
シックなデザインなので これなら日常使いできますよね！
With a chic design like this, you can definitely use it every day, right?
そして『マリンとドキドキ海水浴』という ちょっとラブラブなASMRボイスもあります！
And there's also a sweet ASMR voice, "Heart-throbbing Sea Bathing with Marine"!
ちょっとグイグイ行かせてもらうので 覚悟の準備をしておいてください！
I'll be a bit pushy in it, so be prepared!
そしてそして！フルセット購入特典は……
And furthermore! The full set purchase bonus is...
チケット風カード！
a ticket-style card!
昨日ね 夏の野外フェスに出演したところなので
Since I just performed at a summer outdoor fest yesterday,
ちょっと意識してサマーフェスチケット風です！
I designed it with that in mind as a summer fest ticket!
数量限定ver.は直筆メッセージ入り
The limited edition comes with a handwritten message,
通常ver.は複製直筆メッセージ入りです！
and the standard version comes with a printed handwritten message!
記念に是非是非GETしてください！
Please be sure to get it as a keepsake!
そしてこの後は メンバーシップ限定で水着の撮影会を行います！
And right after this, we'll have a swimsuit photoshoot stream for members only!
いろんな差分をお見せするので いっぱい堪能してくださいね！
I'll be showing various expression/pose variations, so please enjoy!
マリンの面談はゲリラが多めらしいので
Since my member chats tend to be unannounced streams,
これを機に是非他の面談アーカイブと合わせてメンバーシップいかがでしょうか！
how about joining membership to check out past chat archives too?
また後日 振り返り配信で今日のいろんな裏話を聞いてください！
Later on in a recap stream, please come hear behind-the-scenes stories!
それじゃあ行きますよー！出航～！
Alright, here we go! Ahoy~!
あー
Ah~